One of the great things about Codex is
that right inside of it, it can make
images for you. As you can see right
here, I gave it these three images and I
said, "Hey, I need a YouTube thumbnail."
I described what I want and then I got
it right here. But, if I asked it to
turn this into an animated video, it
wouldn't be able to do it with its
native capabilities. It would have to
find some other form. It would have to
build code. Like here, it wants to use
Hyperframes. So, typically what you do
is you connect it to something like
Higgsfield that has a bunch of video and
image models like Seedance 2.5 and all
of these other ones like Klang and
Omniflash and Minimax. The problem with
Higgsfield was that it was way more
expensive because you had to get on a
subscription. If we look at the monthly,
if you wanted to use Seedance 2.5, you
had to be on a 60 bucks a month plan and
you still had a limited number of
credits. But, Higgsfield just actually
dropped an API, which means that you can
actually just pay per usage. Meaning,
you can connect Codex to Higgsfield API
and then you're not actually paying
every single month. You're only paying
for the times that you actually make
requests. So, today I'm just going to
show you real quick how easy this is to
set up. So, let's get right into it. So,
this is a completely separate account.
What you're going to do is you're going
to go to Google and you're going to type
in Higgsfield API and then you're pretty
much going to click on this first link
right here and it's going to take you to
this API dashboard where you'll be able
to create your own key and create your
own account. And when you sign up,
you're going to get a ton of discounts
because they just dropped this, which is
15% off sale models, up to 50% off your
favorites, and you get 15 bucks right
away in your account to play with. So,
create an account and then when you're
inside of that, it's going to look like
this. What you're going to want to do is
you're going to go to either the quick
start on this right-hand side and you
can copy this prompt if you want, but
you don't have to. It's it's a lot
easier than that. But, you do have to
make an API key. So, you'll click on
create API key, you'll type in a name,
so I'll just call this one demo, and
you'll create your key. And then all you
have to do is copy this key right here
and then hop into Codex and I'll show
you what to do next. Real quick, before
we hop into Codex, I just wanted to show
you guys how to make sure you take full
advantage of this launch because this is
a 7-day limited offer. So, these things
up here that we see, 15% off all sale
models, that is just when you sign up,
you'll already have that discount. In
order to get up to 50% off your picks,
you have to come into the pricing
section and it says choose three models
with max discount up to 50% off. And
then you would just come in here and
choose two video models and one image
model and you can see all of the prices
over here. As you can see, with 30% off,
we would be getting it for this price
compared to the original current price.
And then the last one is getting 15 free
dollars to play with on your account.
All you have to do here is connect a
credit card and use an eligible business
domain email. And then once you've
claimed all of that stuff, you now have
that API key, you now have everything
set up and you can run 30 generations at
a time. So let's hop back into Codex and
I can show you how to get this all set
up. So you're going to open up a new
chat and you're just going to say, "Hey,
inside of my .env file, can you just
create me a placeholder for Higgs Field
API? I'm going to drop you in a Higgs
Field API key and then you can just
figure out how that all works so we can
start running some image and video
generations." And then just shoot that
off and it will tell you exactly where
to paste in your key. You don't want to
paste it right in here into the chat
thread, you want to paste it into the
.env file. So you can see I already have
that in there, so it says, "Hey, that
already exists." it doesn't, it'll give
you a placeholder and then all you have
to do is ask for the file path so you
can actually open this up. So I could
right click this, go to open with and I
can just open this with whatever I want.
I'll choose default app. That opens up
my notes where I can go ahead and see
right here it added Higgs Field API key
and then you will just go ahead and
paste in your API key right there. And
then make sure you save that before you
close out of it and then just go, "Okay,
cool. I put in that API key. Can you see
what models are available for me through
that Higgs Field API?" And then just go
ahead and shoot off a test video
generation where there is a man sitting
at a laptop using Higgs Field and using
Codex to generate videos. But you guys
don't have to worry about that at all
because I have this skill right here
called Higgs Field API generations and
it has all these defaults in here. It
has all of the settings, it has all of
the different things that you might need
or you would have your agent have to
normally go out and do research on.
Everything's right here. So basically
all you have to do is you've put in your
Higgs Field API key into your .env and
now you can see it's basically going to
use that whenever you need an image or a
video and it knows exactly how to work
with Higgsfield API. It knows about all
of the different functionality and
options that it has in there, and now
it's just generating me a bunch of
different images and videos that you can
see right here on screen with just using
natural language. So, pretty cool stuff.
If you want to grab this skill, it's
completely free in my free school
community. Link for that is down in the
description. Just get into the free
school community, you're going to go to
classroom and click on all YouTube
resources, and there will be a huge
database with a bunch of resources. You
should be able to find it right in
there. And that skill is also going to
tell you exactly how much each of your
generations cost you so that you don't
have to be constantly going back into
your Higgsfield dashboard to look at the
analytics. You will just get that right
there in your chat thread. So, while
that's running, I'll just go over here
and show you real quick what actually
this stuff can look like. So, we have
Higgsfield API benchmark. Out of all of
these videos that I generated, so I'll
show you each one like how much it
costed, or sorry, cost. My goodness. How
dare I? You can see that the total spend
for these was $7.40.
And we were using models like C-Dance
2.5. And once again, this would have
been only available to us on a 60 bucks
a month plan. And then you're just
sitting there paying 60 bucks a month
even if you don't generate anything that
month. So, anyways, we have some video
outputs here. You can see this is
C-Dance 2.5. This one has no audio, but
you can generate these with audio as
well. So, that's a super super clean
shot. Same exact prompt went off to
Kling 3.0. And this one has, I don't
know, those letters look a little bit
different compared to that image, but
they have similar sort of like
background. The letters in this one are
also off. So, it's really good to get in
here and shoot off the same prompt to a
bunch of different AI models and see
which one comes back best. In this case,
Nova came through only as Nova in
C-Dance 2.5. So, in this case it was the
best. But of course, with C-Dance 2.5
you are going to be paying a little bit
more, but once again, it's only pay per
usage. So, here this one was 1.6 bucks.
This one was only about 20 cents, and
this one was only about 50 cents. But
they also can generate sound. So, let me
play you guys a few examples of some UGC
content, and we'll take a look at the
cost as well.
>> I used to skip breakfast.
Now, I grab Nova protein coffee.
20 g of protein, real coffee,
and I'm out the door.
>> So, this was Cidens 2.5 and it was
$3.23.
Here is Kling 3.0.
>> I used to skip breakfast. Now, I grab
Nova protein coffee. 20 g of protein,
real coffee, and I'm out the door.
>> And as far as realism, I think Kling 3.0
did a really, really good job here with
this character, you know, selfie style
UGC for only 60 cents. Whereas this one
you wouldn't say, I don't know. It's
like it's not noticeably better as far
as like makes a huge difference. But in
general, I mean Cidens 2.5 is, in my
opinion, the leading video generation
model right here. But we also have Mini
Max and this one was $1.10.
>> I used to skip breakfast. Now, I grab
Nova protein coffee. 20 g of protein,
real coffee,
>> Anyways, I think that this one was
clearly the worst out of just these
three very, very simple videos. But it's
important, like I said, shoot off the
same prompts at different models, see
how the cost differs, see how the
quality differs, see what they're good
at. Because Cidens 2.5 might be the best
at like people and product shots, but
maybe Mini Max or Kling is better at
different sort of like cartoon
animations or something like that. And
then of course, you can use Codex image
generation, GBT image 2.5 is really,
really good. It's probably my favorite.
But there are also other image models
you can try out like Higgsfield
Marketing Studio here or Grok Imagine
2.0, Soul 2.0. And these are obviously
much cheaper than generating videos. But
I did take this exact same prompt and
put it into Codex. And this is what we
got here. So, if you like this better,
then maybe you want to just stick with
GBT 2.5. And then you also have the
benefit of this just counting towards
your Codex subscription or your ChatGPT
subscription rather than paying
separately per usage for that. Anyways,
hopping back here into Codex, what's
cool about this is Codex will go ahead
and do all the research. So, you don't
have to think about the API endpoints.
You don't have to give it anything else.
You just tell it to figure it all out
and it will. And so, that's why back in
here you can copy this prompt if you
want or you can just say like figure it
out because you can see this prompt is
literally pointing it to the actual
Higgs Field API documentation. You can
see it says your key authenticated
successfully, the live catalog returned
76 endpoints, 18 are text to video, 44
are image to video, 11 are text to
image, and plus there's a few other
routes. And it's going to use SeaDance
2.0 for this first run. The request was
accepted with this ID and now it's
basically just going to keep polling on
that request until the generation is
done. And polling just means it's going
to check in and then if it's not done
it's going to wait and it's going to
check in again if it's not done it's
going to wait and it's going to keep
polling or checking until that video is
actually done and then it will download
the MP4 locally. And so while this is
finishing up, let me just show you what
else is available inside of the Higgs
Field API. If you go to pricing, right
now it says that you can get up to 50%
off. And this is only for the next 7
days, so if you're watching this early,
go here and you can choose two video and
one image models to get 50% off on. So
you'll literally just come in here and
it will say, "Hey, what are your models
you want to choose?" I personally chose
SeaDance 2.5 and Kling 3.0. And then for
the image model I chose the Marketing
Studio image. But then you can just go
ahead and look at all of the models in
here and you can see the different modes
that they run in like standard or turbo
or, you know, 4K, whatever it is. And
you can see all of the information about
all these different types of models and
their pricing. And then the analytics
will basically just show you how much
you've spent, um what is your request
looking like, what are the models you
like to use, and things like that. So
just a pretty little analytics dashboard
for you. You can see we have this video
back. Now, this is already looking a
little bit weird with SeaDance 2.0
because the laptop is facing the wrong
way, but let's give this a quick play.
Now, I'm really not quite sure if
anybody uses a laptop like that, but
either way this was SeaDance 2.0 and
there is a better model out there now.
But what's important to realize is that
the model isn't just going to run
perfectly for you. You have to be able
to prompt it in the right way and you
will start to build skills around how
you like to prompt image generations and
video generations and that's where this
gets really powerful is when you work in
all of these different skills, and you
can add things too like your brand
guidelines or a consistent character
that you want to have, and then over
time your ability to just inside of
Codex generate these different videos
and image assets is going to get better
and better. Now, I did want to end off
this video talking about is this
actually cheaper? And the answer is yes
and no. It all depends on the break-even
point. Because now that you're being
charged per usage rather than based on
your credits that reset every month,
there's a break-even point. And if
you're paying per usage to the point
where you're going over that break-even
point, then this is probably where you'd
want to be on a subscription. But, if
you're only infrequently generating
videos and images on a monthly basis,
and you're below that break-even point,
then it's much cheaper obviously to be
on the pay-per-usage billing. Especially
when you're trying to figure out like
what is your cadence, then starting with
pay-per-usage is a lot safer than just
committing to a monthly subscription.
And so, I've run the math here, and on
the plus and ultra plans within Hatch
Field, this is what it would kind of
look like as far as those break-even
points. So, if you're on the plus
monthly, it's about fewer than 19 clips.
And if you're on the plus annual, then
it's roughly 16 clips. And if you're
below that, then the API makes more
sense. If you're on ultra, it looks like
50 on monthly or 39 on annual. So,
ultimately, these are the three kind of
questions I wanted to answer here. If
you're maxing out your subscription plan
every single month consistently, then
you probably just want to stay on a
subscription. If you're only generating
things occasionally like maybe some
months you'll run, you know, 15 videos,
some months you won't do any at all,
then API will win. And if you need
programmatic workflows or you want to
bake this API into your own, I don't
know, your own website or SaaS product
or your own internal tools or whatever
it is, then the API is going to win
there as well. So, it's always hard in
the AI space or in the text space to
just come out of the gate and say, "Yes,
this is objectively cheaper." or "Yes,
this is objectively better." It's always
very situational. So, hopefully this all
kind of makes sense and you can kind of
use this to figure out in your specific
situation what is probably the right
path for you. And what's really cool is
when you get all that dialed in, you can
do all of this in bulk. So, we've
actually done things where we've
generated assets for like our events or
for, you know, ads or whatever it is,
and we basically just use Codex or
Claude to help us brainstorm all the
briefs and all the angles, and then we
just shoot off a bunch of workers to
generate all those assets. And then you
wake up and everything is done. So,
anyways guys, that is going to do it for
this one. I hope you enjoyed, you
learned something new, and if you did,
please give it a like, it helps me out a
ton. And as always, I appreciate you
guys making it to the end of the video,
and I'll see you on the next one.
Thanks, everyone.